(upbeat music)
Hi everyone!
As new sellers, we would love to check our sales all the time, right?
It's great if it's always going upward, but what if we see a sales dip?
Today I'm going to talk about a checklist that you can go through quickly to self-diagnose any sales
downward trend.
First, I would go to the Account Health page to see if there is any policy warning, violation, or
compliance issues that you have to deal with to get your listing reactivated.
The dashboard
is very self-explanatory and you should be able to spot the issues right away.
Second
place I will see is pricing health under pricing on Amazon.
It will tell you if there's any
of your ASINs loses buy box due to pricing issues.
And third place I will look at would
be the inactive listing tab under manage all inventory.
It will show you all the listings
that are not active due to common reason out of stock or softer listing suppression
issues such as any problems with your title, any problems with your images that cause
listing suppressions.
The fourth place, what if your PPC is not running due to payment
failure?
That's the fourth place I will look.
If there is any payment issue with your PPC,
it will show up on top of the PPC console page as a red banner and tell you that your
PPC is currently paused because the payment doesn't go through.
Now the second part would
be softer reasons why you see a sudden sales dip, including your active running coupon
or your active running Lightning Deal or best deal.
Are there any errors with them?
If there
is any error, you are going to see a need attention badge underneath that particular coupon or
that particular deal so that you can go in quickly and fix it.
Usually the common reason
for deal or coupon suppression is also pricing issues.
And then the promotions that are important
to you, I would suggest that you go and check in and see if those promotions are expired
without you knowing it or they're running out of budget already, which is also a reason
why they're not running.
The last thing I would check is the best seller rank.
It's
on top of Amazon.
com page.
You can check for your niche is your ASIN ranking well relative
to other competitors.
I actually check that daily to make sure my ASIN is well positioned
within my niche.
So those are all the checklists that we should quickly look.
Happy selling!